<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Usage on WorkflowFM Composer</title><link>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/</link><description>Recent content in Usage on WorkflowFM Composer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:07:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quick Start</title><link>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/quick/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:07:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/quick/</guid><description>A quick overview of some of the features is described in the following tasks:
Create Click on the Create Process icon. Double click on the process box labelled P1 to rename the process. Double click on one of the edges (initially labelled X) to rename the corresponding resource. Double click on one of the small, resource circles to add a new branch. Right-click on one of the small, resource circles to add a branch of different type (from parallel to optional and vice-versa) or to delete a branch.</description></item><item><title>Create &amp; Edit</title><link>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/edit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:07:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/edit/</guid><description>Clicking on the Create Process icon at any time opens a new window for creating a new atomic process. Right-clicking on an atomic process in the Processes list on the left and then clicking the Edit Process option opens the same window to allow edits. The available functionality is described below.
Actions can be undone/redone at any time using the undo/redo arrows at the top, or Ctrl-Z and Ctrl-Y respectively.</description></item><item><title>Compose</title><link>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/compose/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:07:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/compose/</guid><description>Composition involves the combination of 2 processes (binary compositions) in a single composite process.
This requires an active Workspace. A new workspace can be created using the Create Workspace icon. Processes can be added to the workspace by double-clicking them in the Processes list on the left or by right-clicking them and selecting the Add Graph option. Once added, processes can be composed together in 3 ways:</description></item><item><title>Store &amp; Verify</title><link>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/verify/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:07:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/verify/</guid><description>Store Storing an intermediate composition allows the creation of a new, composite process that can be reused in the same way as atomic processes.
The expectation here is that the user composes processes together using composition actions and generating intermediate compositions. Once they are happy with a particular composition and they want to keep it for further use as a new process, they can store it.
This can be accomplished by right clicking on an intermediate composition of a workspace in the Compositions list on the left.</description></item><item><title>Deploy</title><link>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/deploy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:07:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/deploy/</guid><description>The reasoner can automatically generate executable Scala code for process compositions, including code templates for the involved resource types and atomic processes.
The code relies on the use of the WorkflowFM PEW execution engine.
This can be accomplished by right-clicking on a composite process and selecting the Deploy in Scala option. This will open a new window with the appropriate dialog for deploying code. Using the Ski example, the window is shown below:</description></item><item><title>Other</title><link>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/other/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:07:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/use/other/</guid><description>Some other available functionality is described here.
Show Graph Once a composite process or an intermediate composition is created, its graph can be viewed on a separate window.
This can be accomplished by right-clicking the composition and selecting the Show Graph option. The full graph is also shown when hovering above the blue process box of a (collapsed) composite process. This can be particularly useful for composite processes which appear as a single atomic process in subsequent compositions.</description></item></channel></rss>