<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reference on WorkflowFM Composer</title><link>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/reference/</link><description>Recent content in Reference on WorkflowFM Composer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:07:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Examples</title><link>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/reference/examples/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:07:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/reference/examples/</guid><description>A list of examples is available in the default installation of the client. You can inspect them by loading the corresponding file, verifying all processes and compositions and viewing their graphs.
The following examples are included:
SimpleCopyAndSequence.json: Simple example demonstrating the copy node and 2 separate methods of serial sequential composition. Inspection of the graph and underlying π-calculus structure shows the difference between composing right-to-left (simpler structure) and left-to-right (introduces axiom buffers).</description></item><item><title>Graph elements</title><link>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/reference/graph/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:07:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/reference/graph/</guid><description>The following is a complete list of the visual elements, including nodes (vertices) and edges, that can be encountered in a process graph.
Vertices Name Visual Description Resource An input or output resource. Atomic Process An atomic process. Composite Process A composite process. Copy node A process with a single input and multiple parallel outputs of the same type is assumed to be a copy process that makes multiple copies of its input.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/reference/configuration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:07:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-composer/client/reference/configuration/</guid><description>Configuration values are stored in a .workflowfm directory at the user's home directory, defaulting in the composer.properties file.
It is not necessary to explicitly set any of these configuration parameters, but it is possible to tweak the behaviour of the client in some ways if desired.
You can manually set parameters in the configuration file following the standard .properties file format, variable = value. You can also create a custom property file to be used instead of the default file.</description></item></channel></rss>